Christensen, C. Roland (Carl Roland), 1919-1999. C. Roland Christensen Papers, 1931-1998: A Finding Aid
C. Roland Christensen papers, 1931-1998
Baker Library, Harvard Business School
Arch GA 13.4
Christensen, C. Roland (Carl Roland), 1919-1999
33.8 linear feet (81 boxes)
11 megabytes (content from 55 disks)
Research, teaching materials, writings, speeches, administrative records, audio recordings and other papers of Harvard Business School professor C. Roland Christensen.
Provenance:
Gift of C. Roland Christensen, 1985, 1990, 1997, 1998, 2007.
This collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and provide valid photo identification before using this collection.
Materials stored offsite. Please contact histcollref@hbs.edu for more information.
Restricted material has been identified and separated. Note that box and folder lists of restricted material have been redacted.
Digital use copies in this collection can be accessed only onsite in the de Gaspé Beaubien Reading Room. To request access please contact histcollref@hbs.edu prior to visiting the library.
Related Collections:
Christensen’s HBS doctoral dissertation, “Management Succession in Small and Growing Enterprises,” 1953 is filed with the HBS Archives Thesis Collection.
Biographical Note:
Carl Roland Christensen was born in Tyler, Minnesota, in 1919, the son of teachers. He received his Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of Iowa in 1941 and a Master of Business Administration and Doctor of Commercial Science degree from Harvard Business School in 1943 and 1953, respectively. During and immediately following World War II he served as a Captain in the U.S. Army Quartermaster Corps, 1943-1946.
Christensen became a Research Assistant in Business Administration at Harvard Business School in 1946 and an Instructor in Business Administration in 1947. He was promoted to Assistant Professor (1948) and Associate Professor (1954), becoming a full Professor of Business Administration in 1958, and the George F. Baker, Jr. Professor of Business Administration in 1963. Appointed as the Robert Walmsey University Professor by Harvard president Derek Bok in 1984, Christensen was the first Harvard Business School faculty member to become a University Professor. In fact, Christensen played a major role in the development of the Derek Bok Center, established in 1975 to heighten the quality of undergraduate instruction at Harvard. Within the Harvard community, Christensen taught at the Harvard Law School, the Harvard Medical School, the Graduate School of Education and the School of Public Health. His teaching activities outside of the Harvard community included teaching at IMEDE, an international school of management in Laussane, Switzerland, the Stanford Graduate School of Business, and the Sloan School of Management at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
Business Policy, case method instruction and developing discussion leadership skills were Christensen's major areas of teaching, study and research throughout his career. In addition, as the director of many businesses, Christensen observed various problems associated with the decision-making process and the effective functioning of boards of directors. His research interests included investigations into ways of improving the operation of such boards.
Christensen is widely recognized as one of the leading experts on the art of teaching by discussion and on the effective use of the case method and field studies in education. His teaching methods were designed to promote the active involvement of students, encouraging them to express, share, and compare ideas by using classroom techniques that are sensitive to the needs of individual students without surrendering control of the instructional process. The case method at HBS confronts students with problems encountered by managers and uses the problems as a basis for exploring theoretical concepts as well as practical issues. At the request of Derek Bok in the mid 1970s, Christensen built on these concepts and developed two influential seminars designed to improve the quality of teaching: Developing Discussion Leadership Skills and Teaching By the Case Method. For over twenty years, Christensen organized and co-taught classes for university faculty members, both within and beyond the Harvard community, enabling them to hone their skills at leading discussions and molding their abilities to question, listen, and respond. In fact, although formally retired in 1990, Christensen was actively engaged in teaching seminars on discussion and case method teaching until shortly before his death.
Christensen passed away on August 28, 1999 in Nashville, Tennessee.
Scope and Content Note:
The collection consists of annotated cases, teaching notes and other course materials, case development files, correspondence, speeches, administrative records, audio recordings, writings and drafts of publications related to teaching. The annotated cases and supporting course materials such as course outlines, reading lists, memoranda, seating charts, rosters and transcripts of presentations, illustrate Christensen's approach to teaching as well as his questioning, discussion and course management techniques. Specific HBS courses represented are Field Studies (1964-1984), Administrative Policy (1947-1953) and Business Policy (1951-1979). Christensen's case development activities are illustrated through the Nike, Inc. Case Development Files, which include handwritten notes and questions as well as a transcript of an interview with Nike co-founder Philip Knight. The records relating to the Colloquium on Teaching by the Case Method held in 1984 provide a number of perspectives expressed by various speakers concerning the case method and its effectiveness.
Materials relating to Christensen's efforts to improve the teaching skills of university professors by Developing Discussion Leadership Skills and Teaching By the Case Method courses include annotated cases developed by Christensen, Dr. Abby J. Hansen and others specifically for these courses. Other teaching and seminar planning materials include topical notes, discussion questions, correspondence, teaching plans, memoranda, agendas, schedules, programs and catalogs of seminar participants. Also included are topical notes, personal reflections, periodical clippings, cartoons and quotations assembled by Christensen that provide insight into his personal teaching philosophy. Other records include materials related to Christensen's books Teaching and the Case Method and Education for Judgment: The Artistry of Discussion Leadership, publications not authored by Christensen and other materials. Also included are digital drafts of Teaching and the Case Method and other draft material on teaching and class discussion used in Christensen's books and seminars.
Research materials include a group of articles maintained by Christensen as "Article Files." Speeches made by Christensen between 1963 and 1996 elucidate Christensen's thoughts on the nature of teaching and on various methods of instruction.
Christensen's administrative activities are represented by correspondence, handwritten notes, memos, guidelines, course outlines, reports, exams, course evaluations and other materials related to Administrative Policy and Business Policy courses. Christensen's MBA Review Committee records (a committee assembled with the purpose of creating a strategic plan for the MBA program at HBS), include memos, reports, notes and related documents from 1959-1961.
Audiovisual records include an audio recording and transcription of a 1997 interview between Christensen and Albert Bartovics and Carole Foster about the development of Business Policy cases and their use in HBS courses. Also included are audio recordings of Christensen speaking at the Cotting Library in 1982, a 1988 interview with Bob Eccles, and a video recording entitled Case Video to Accompany Business Policy Text and Cases, which contains video segments of a number of instructors, including Christensen, to accompany Business Policy: Text and Cases, 7th Ed, a book that Christensen co-authored.
Series Outline
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1959-1980
Series II. HBS Teaching Records, 1931-1998
Subseries A. Annotated Cases, circa 1948-1990
Subseries B. Business Policy Teaching Files, 1948-1990
Subseries C. Case Development Files, Nike, Inc., 1983-1984
Subseries D. Colloquium on Teaching by the Case Method, 1984-1988
Subseries E. Field Studies, 1964-1984
Subseries F. Teaching Materials and Course Development, 1947-1996
Subseries G. Teaching About Teaching, 1931-1998
i. Annotated Cases Used for Teaching About Teaching, circa 1940-1998
ii. Reflections, 1975-1997
iii. Seminar Teaching Materials, circa 1950s-1997
iv. General, 1931-1998
Series III. Research, Writings and Speeches, 1946-1996
Subseries A. Writings and Speeches, 1960-1996
Subseries B. Article Files, 1946-1974
Series IV. HBS Administrative Files, 1946-1970
Subseries A. Administrative and Academic Planning Files, 1946-1970
Subseries B. MBA Review Committee Files, 1959-1961
Series V. Audiovisual Records, 1982-1997
Detailed Description of the Collection
- I. Correspondence, 1959-1980
  The series consists of Christensen’s correspondence with Ernest Arbuckle, Dean of Stanford Business School, and supporting materials, regarding approaches to business school curricula.
  - Arbuckle, Ernest (Dean of Stanford Business School), 1959-1980 (Box 1, f. 1)
- II. HBS Teaching Records, 1931-1998
  This series consists primarily of printed cases with associated notes and annotations as well as other teaching notes and supporting materials. Also included are Nike case development files, materials on the 1984 Colloquium on Teaching by the Case Method, Field Studies course material, records related to Christensen's seminars on discussion and case method teaching, as well as topical notes and reflections related to teaching. This series also contains digital content of Teaching and the Case Method and of work relating to teaching and class discussion.
  - A. Annotated Cases, circa 1948-1990
    Case teaching files, including annotated cases, handwritten notes, questions, and supporting materials used by Christensen to teach classes at HBS are represented. Many materials relate to the teaching of Business Policy courses. The files in Subseries A are similar those in Subseries B, Business Policy Teaching Files, 1948-1990, which Christensen separately maintained as "Business Policy Teaching Files." Cases in Subseries A seem to have been more actively used by Christensen, while the cases in Subseries B seem to have been used more regularly as a reference resource for selecting or comparing cases. Cases developed for the teaching of Developing Discussion Leadership Skills and Teaching By the Case Method seminars can be found in Subseries G, Subgroup I, Annotated Cases Used for Teaching About Teaching, circa 1940-1998.
    - Acoustic Research, Inc. (A), BP 639 (Box 1, f. 2)
    - Acoustic Research, Inc. (B), BP 640 (Box 1, f. 3)
    - Acoustic Research, Inc. (C), BP 641 (Box 1, f. 4)
    - Acoustic Research, Inc. (D), BP 830 (Box 1, f. 5)
    - Adams Corporation (Box 1, f. 6)
    - Adams, John, 6-373-157 (Box 1, f. 7)
    - Advance Aircraft Co., BP 437 (Box 1, f. 8)
    - Air, Inc., OB 107 (Box 1, f. 9)
    - Air Products and Chemicals, Inc., 4-375-370 (Box 1, f. 10)
    - Albert Manufacturing Co., EA-A 249 (Box 1, f. 11)
    - American Broadcasting - Paramount Theaters, BP 589 (Box 1, f. 12)
    - American Broadcasting - Paramount Theaters (A), BP 590 (Box 1, f. 13)
    - American Broadcasting - Paramount Theaters (B), BP 591 (Box 2, f. 1)
    - American Broadcasting - Paramount Theaters (C), BP 592 (Box 2, f. 2)
    - American Broadcasting - Paramount Theaters, notes, BP 670 (Box 2, f. 3)
    - American Broadcasting Theaters, public policy (Box 2, f. 4)
    - American District Telegraph Co., 4-375-082 (Box 2, f. 5)
    - American Motors Corporation, 9-374-045 (Box 2, f. 6)
    - American Motors Corporation, BP 765 (Box 2, f. 7)
    - American Motors Corporation (B), BP 840 (Box 2, f. 8)
    - American Motors Corporation (C), BP 861 (Box 2, f. 9)
    - American Motors Corporation (D), BP 880 (Box 2, f. 10)
    - American Motors Corporation (E), BP 907 (Box 2, f. 11)
    - American Motors Corporation (F) (Box 2, f. 12)
    - American Motors Corporation, merger exercise, (1)(2), BP 881- BP 882 (Box 2, f. 13)
    - American Motors Corporation, part II, 4-372-350 (Box 2, f. 14-15)
    - American Motors Corporation, Recent Events at AMC, BP 907r (Box 2, f. 16)
    - Anglo-Chilean Consolidated Nitrate Corporation, BP 366 (Box 2, f. 17)
    - "Apologetics of Managerialism," by E.S. Mason (Box 2, f. 18)
    - Appalachian Tanneries Corporation, BP 350 (Box 2, f. 19)
    - Associated Electrical Manufacturers Business Group, 4-373-085 (Box 2, f. 20)
    - Associated Petroleum, BP 900r (Box 3, f. 1)
    - Association of Home Appliance Manufacturers, 4-372-344 (Box 3, f. 2)
    - Automobile Safety (Box 3, f. 3)
    - Avery, Sewell Lee, SPM 8 (Box 3, f. 4)
    - Baker Metal and Foil Co., BP 390 (Box 3, f. 5)
    - Ballard Co., BP 394 (Box 3, f. 6)
    - Baltimore Lithographing Co., BP 372 (Box 3, f. 7)
    - Barclay, Inc. (A), 4-374-165 (Box 3, f. 8)
    - Barclay, Inc. (B), 4-374-166 (Box 3, f. 9)
    - Barclay, Inc. (C), 4-374-167 (Box 3, f. 10)
    - Barclay, Inc. (D), 4-374-168 (Box 3, f. 11)
    - Bard Co. (A), BP 580 (Box 3, f. 12)
    - Bard Co. (A)(abbreviated), BP 580 (Box 3, f. 13)
    - Bard Co. (B), BP 581 (Box 3, f. 14)
    - Barr, C.W., Co., BP 469 (Box 3, f. 15)
    - Basic Industries, Inc., BP 899 (Box 4, f. 1)
    - Bay State Abrasive Products Co., BP 444 (Box 4, f. 2)
    - Bay State Abrasive Products Co. (B), BP 573 (Box 4, f. 3)
    - Beech Aircraft Corporation, BP 933 (Box 4, f. 4)
    - Benedict, Lawrence, Letter from, BP 461 (Box 4, f. 5)
    - Benton, Charles, BP 565 (Box 4, f. 6)
    - Berkeley Co., BP 429 (Box 4, f. 7)
    - Bestor Corporation, BP 347 (Box 4, f. 8)
    - Bic Pen Corporation (Box 4, f. 9)
    - Bic Pen Corporation (A), 4-374-305 (Box 4, f. 10)
    - Bic Pen Corporation (A), 4-374-305 (Box 5, f. 1)
    - Bic Pen Corporation (B), 4-374-306 (Box 5, f. 2)
    - Blakeston and Wilson, BP 436r (Box 5, f. 3)
    - Blow-Mold Packers, Inc., 9-372-239 (Box 5, f. 4)
    - Bollinger Brush Corporation, BP 448 (Box 5, f. 5)
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra (A), 4-374-078 (Box 5, f. 6)
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra (B), 4-374-079 (Box 5, f. 7)
    - Bowen Hat Co., BP 376 (Box 5, f. 8)
    - Bramer Restaurant Co., BP 396 (Box 5, f. 9)
    - Brayton Machine Co., BP 346 (Box 5, f. 10)
    - Breck, Thomas, BP 455 (Box 5, f. 11)
    - Breitman and Co., BP 740 (Box 6, f. 1)
    - Breitman and Co. (A), BP 462r (Box 6, f. 2-3)
    - Breitman and Co. (B), BP 462r (B) (Box 6, f. 4-5)
    - Campaign Performance and Private Criticism, GM, BP 982 (Box 6, f. 6-7)
    - Campaign Performance and Private Criticism, GM, I and II, 3-372-026 (Box 6, f. 8)
    - Carmen Co., 4-372-338 (Box 6, f. 9)
    - Carr Steel Co., BP 400 (Box 7, f. 1)
    - Carter, William (Box 7, f. 2)
    - Case, J.I., Co. (A), BP 763r (Box 7, f. 3)
    - Case, J.I., Co. (B), BP 868 (Box 7, f. 4)
    - Castengo Steel Co., BP 425 (Box 7, f. 5)
    - Central Texas Cement Co., BP 453 (Box 7, f. 6-7)
    - Chain Saw Industry in 1978, 9-379-176 (Box 7, f. 8)
    - Charles River, EA-G 325 (Box 7, f. 9)
    - Charles River Breeding Laboratories, 4-376-262 (Box 7, f. 10)
    - Cherokee Car and Foundry Co., BP 449 (Box 7, f. 11)
    - Chrysler Corporation, BP II 322 and BP II 288 (Box 7, f. 12)
    - Cluett Peabody and Co., BP 331 and BP 331s (Box 7, f. 13)
    - CML Group, Inc., BP 1018 (Box 8, f. 1)
    - Cold Air Corporation, HP 371 (Box 8, f. 2)
    - Colony Trucking Co., BP 604r (Box 8, f. 3)
    - Colony Trucking Co. (A), BP 604 (Box 8, f. 4)
    - Colony Trucking Co. (B), BP 605 (Box 8, f. 5)
    - Compagnie Chillon Electronique, GM 81, IMEDE (Box 8, f. 6)
    - Comparative Strategies of the Four Major Tire and Rubber Producers, BP 852 (Box 8, f. 7)
    - Consolidated Drugs, Inc., EA-G 94 (Box 8, f. 8)
    - Consolidated Petroleum Corporation (revised and condensed) (Box 8, f. 9)
    - Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation (A)(B), BP 427r(A) and BP 427r(B) (Box 8, f. 10)
    - Continental Jewelry Co., BP 401 (Box 8, f. 11)
    - Continental Watchmakers Co., BP 647 (Box 8, f. 12)
    - "The Corporation: How Much Power, What Scope?" by Carl Kaysen, BP 774 (Box 9, f. 1)
    - Crown Cork and Seal Co., 9-378-024 (Box 9, f. 2)
    - Crown Cork and Seal Co., BP 800 (Box 9, f. 3-4)
    - Crown Cork and Seal Co. (B) (Box 9, f. 5)
    - Custom Packaging Co., BP 925 (Box 9, f. 6-7)
    - DAAG Europe (A), 9-374-037 (Box 9, f. 8)
    - Dairy Products Co., BP 337 (Box 9, f. 9)
    - Dale Petroleum Co. (A), BP 463 (Box 9, f. 10)
    - Dale Petroleum Co. (B), BP 464 (Box 9, f. 11)
    - Dale Petroleum Co. (C), BP 465 (Box 10, f. 1)
    - Danford Rubber Co., BP 442 (Box 10, f. 2)
    - Dansk Designs, Ltd., BP 1004 (Box 10, f. 3-4)
    - Deering Shoe Co. (B), BP 410 (Box 10, f. 5)
    - Dennison Manufacturing Co. (A)(B) (revised), BP 997 (Box 10, f. 6)
    - Dennison Manufacturing Co. (B), BP 897 (Box 10, f. 7)
    - Dennison Manufacturing Co. (C), BP 898 (Box 10, f. 8)
    - Design and Manufacturing Corporation, 4-372-343 (Box 10, f. 9)
    - Dexter Corporation, 9-379-112 (Box 10, f. 10)
    - Directors (1942), BP 406 (Box 10, f. 11)
    - Dr. Pepper Co. (Box 10, f. 12)
    - Dr. Pepper Co., 1-377-146 (Box 11, f. 1-2)
    - Drug, Inc., BP 275 (Box 11, f. 3)
    - Drug Industry: Competitive Strategies, BP 778 (Box 11, f. 4)
    - Drug Industry, Note on U.S. Prescription, BP 760 (Box 11, f. 5)
    - Drug Industry, Notes on, Medical, Chemical, and Ethical, BP 495 (Box 11, f. 6)
    - Drug Industry, The Kefauver Investigation, BP 761 (Box 11, f. 7)
    - Dumont Laboratories, Inc., BP 441 (Box 11, f. 8)
    - Dumont Laboratories, Inc., BP 452 (revised) (Box 11, f. 9)
    - Dunaway Corporation, BP 432 (Box 12, f. 1)
    - The Dupont Story, 1-372-165 (Box 12, f. 2-3)
    - Dynamit-Nobel A.G., BP 926 (Box 12, f. 4)
    - Eastern Rubber Products, BP 403 (Box 12, f. 5)
    - Eastman Kodak Co. (A)(B), BP 876 and BP 877 (Box 12, f. 6)
    - Economic Theories of Competition and the Anti-Trust Law, BP 805 (Box 12, f. 7)
    - Edwards, John, EA-A 2 (Box 12, f. 8)
    - E G & G, Inc. (A) (condensed), 9-377-027 (Box 12, f. 9)
    - E G & G, Inc. (B), 9-376-188 (Box 12, f. 10)
    - E G & G, Inc., teaching note (Box 12, f. 11)
    - Eleganza International (A) (Box 12, f. 12)
    - Environmental Pressures (A)(B), 4-375-126 and 4-375-127 (Box 12, f. 13)
    - Evaluating Corporate Strategy, BP 738 (Box 13, f. 1)
    - Ex-Cello Corporation, BP 417 (Box 13, f. 2)
    - Executive Compensation, note on, BP 556 (Box 13, f. 3)
    - "Executive Leadership," by A. Zaleznik and A. Jardim, BP 915 (Box 13, f. 4)
    - Farm Equipment Industry, note on, BP 864 (Box 13, f. 5-6)
    - Farm Equipment Manufacturers, note on, BP 893 (Box 13, f. 7)
    - Farr (Loren) & Co., BP 380 (Box 13, f. 8)
    - Fashion Shoe Co., 2-470-037 (Box 13, f. 9)
    - Federal Food Products Co., BP 458 (Box 13, f. 10)
    - Federated Department Stores (A)(B), 8-375-304 (Box 14, f. 1)
    - Federated Department Stores (B) (Box 14, f. 2)
    - Fernald Workshop (revised), 4-376-144 (Box 14, f. 3)
    - Firestone Tire and Rubber Co., BP 843 (Box 14, f. 4)
    - Flawless Foundry and Equipment Co., BP 570 (Box 14, f. 5)
    - Fleetwood Enterprises, 9-374-064 (Box 14, f. 6)
    - Florida Foods, Inc. (A), EA-M 6 (Box 14, f. 7)
    - Florida Products, Ltd., EP 879 (Box 14, f. 8)
    - Forsythe, James, BP 417 (Box 14, f. 9)
    - Freeland Electric Co., BP 397 (Box 14, f. 10)
    - Galvor Co., (A)(B)(C)(D)(E)(F), BP 807 and BP 808 (Box 14, f. 11)
    - General Cinema Corporation, teaching file (Box 15, f. 1)
    - General Electric and the Price Conspiracy Cases, MR 216r1, ICH 9G146 (Box 15, f. 2)
    - General Electric Co., BP 411 (Box 15, f. 3)
    - General Electric Co., Note on Internal Structure, BP 751 (Box 15, f. 4)
    - General Foods Corporation, BP 349 (Box 15, f. 5)
    - General Health Co., 1-380-152 (Box 15, f. 6)
    - General Motors Corporation, BP 683 (Box 15, f. 7)
    - General Motors Corporation (A)(B)(C)(D) (Box 15, f. 8)
    - Gibbons Finance Co. (A) (Box 15, f. 9)
    - Globe Newspaper Co. (Box 15, f. 10)
    - Goodyear Tire and Rubber Co., BP 891 (Box 15, f. 11)
    - Grangesberg (A1), GM 111r (Box 15, f. 12-13)
    - Grangesberg (A2), GM 112r, IMEDE (Box 15, f. 14)
    - Grangesberg (A3), GM 113, IMEDE (Box 15, f. 15)
    - Grangesberg (B1), GM 114, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 1)
    - Grangesberg (B2), GM 115r, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 2)
    - Grangesberg (C1), GM 116r, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 3)
    - Grangesberg (C2), GM 117, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 4)
    - Grangesberg (D1)(D2), GM 118 and GM 119, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 5)
    - Grangesberg (D3), GM 120 (Box 16, f. 6)
    - Grangesberg (E), GM 121, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 7)
    - Grangesberg (E2), GM 122, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 8)
    - Grangesberg (F), GM 123r, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 9)
    - Grangesberg (F2), GM 124r, IMEDE (Box 16, f. 10)
    - Grangesberg Co., group presentation (Box 16, f. 11)
    - Gunnison, William B. Co., BP 432 (Box 16, f. 12)
    - Hallway Co., BP 467 (Box 16, f. 13)
    - Hamilton Watch Co., BP 583 (Box 16, f. 14)
    - Hammond Tire and Rubber Co., BP 851r (Box 17, f. 1)
    - Harder Co., BP 451 (Box 17, f. 2)
    - Harrogate Asphalt Products, OB 78, IMEDE (Box 17, f. 3)
    - Hawaii Best Co. (A)(B), 9-474-795 (Box 17, f. 4)
    - Head Ski Co., BP 888 (Box 17, f. 5)
    - Hedblom (A), BP 927 (Box 17, f. 6)
    - Hedblom (B), BP 928 (Box 17, f. 7)
    - Hedblom (C), BP 929 (Box 17, f. 8)
    - Hedblom (D), BP 930 (Box 17, f. 9)
    - Herbert, Alfred, Ltd. (A), GM 91, IMEDE (Box 17, f. 10)
    - Heublein, Inc. (A), BP 858 (Box 17, f. 11)
    - Heublein, Inc. (B), BP 859 (Box 17, f. 12)
    - Heuer-Leonidas (A), GM 210r1 (Box 17, f. 13)
    - Hewitt Associates, 2-681-063 (Box 18, f. 1)
    - Hilton Hotels Cases, Introduction, BP 601 (Box 18, f. 2)
    - Hilton Hotels (A), BP 505 (Box 18, f. 3)
    - Hilton Hotels (A2), AMP 40 (Box 18, f. 4)
    - Hilton Hotels (Ar), BP 678 (Box 18, f. 5)
    - Hilton Hotels (B), BP 506 (Box 18, f. 6)
    - Hilton Hotels (Br), BP 671 (Box 18, f. 7)
    - Hilton Hotels (C1), BP 507 (Box 18, f. 8)
    - Hilton Hotels (C2), BP 508 (Box 18, f. 9)
    - Hilton Hotels (C3), BP 509 (Box 18, f. 10)
    - Hilton Hotels (CDR), BP 679 (Box 18, f. 11)
    - Hilton Hotels (D), BP 510 (Box 18, f. 12)
    - Hilton Hotels (E1), BP 511 (Box 18, f. 13)
    - Hilton Hotels (E2), BP 512 (Box 18, f. 14)
    - Hilton Hotels (F1), BP 513 (Box 18, f. 15)
    - Hilton Hotels (F2), BP 514 (Box 18, f. 16)
    - Hilton Hotels (F3), BP 515 (Box 18, f. 17)
    - Hilton Hotels (F4), BP 516 (Box 18, f. 18)
    - Hilton Hotels (G1)(G1-2r), BP 517 and BP 741 (Box 18, f. 19)
    - Hilton Hotels (G2), BP 518 (Box 19, f. 1)
    - Hilton Hotels (K1)(K5), extracts, BP 638 (Box 19, f. 2)
    - Hinkley Equipment Co., 1946, BP 431 (Box 19, f. 3)
    - HMH Publishing Co. (A), BP 706 (Box 19, f. 4)
    - HMH Publishing Co. (B), BP 707 (Box 19, f. 5)
    - “How to Lead a Creative Organization,” by D. Ogilvy, BP 745 (Box 19, f. 6)
    - International Business Machines (IBM) (Box 19, f. 7)
    - IBM’s $5,000,000 Gamble, BP 969 (Box 19, f. 8)
    - “The Incredible Electrical Conspiracy,” by R. Smith, BP 750 (Box 19, f. 9)
    - Indian Head Mills (Ar), BP 700 (Box 19, f. 10)
    - Indian Head Mills, exam edition (Box 19, f. 11)
    - The Individual and the Corporation, BP 889 (Box 20, f. 1)
    - Industrial Products, Inc., BP 936 (Box 20, f. 2)
    - Instar Watch Co., BP 584 (Box 20, f. 3)